<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My data and programming blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My data and programming blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Ajna Toth</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 15:55:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My courses</title>
      <link>/my-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 15:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/my-courses/</guid>
      <description>Courses Coursera  An Introduction to Interactive Programming in Python (Part 1), Rice University An Introduction to Interactive Programming in Python (Part 2), Rice University Data Management and Visualization, Wesleyan University Exploratory Data Analysis, Johns Hopkins University Getting and Cleaning Data, Johns Hopkins University Machine Learning Foundations: A Case Study Approach, University of Washington Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) University of Michigan Python Data Structures, University of Michigan R Programming, Johns Hopkins University Regression Models, Johns Hopkins University Reproducible Research, Johns Hopkins University Statistical Inference, Johns Hopkins University The Data Scientist’s Toolbox, Johns Hopkins University  EDX  Basics of Power BI (in progress) Analyzing and Visualizing Data with Power BI (Microsoft) Analyzing and Visualizing Data with Power BI (Davidson) Data Science: Visualization Using Python for Research Foundations of Data Science: Computational Thinking with Python Foundations of Data Science: Inferential Thinking by Resampling Data Analysis for Life Sciences 2: Introduction to Linear Models and Matrix Algebra Data Science and Machine Learning Essentials Introduction to Computational Thinking and Data Science Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python Introduction to R Programming Statistical Thinking for Data Science and Analytics Statistics and R for the Life Sciences Explore Statistics with R Microsoft Professional Program Data Science Certificate:  Introduction to Python for Data Science Principles of Machine Learning Programming with Python for Data Science Data Science Essentials Data Science Orientation Querying with Transact-SQL Statistical Thinking for Data Science and Analytics Analyzing and Visualizing Data with Excel Applied Machine Learning Microsoft Professional Capstone: Data Science    Datacamp  Introduction to Tableau DataAnalyst Track DataScience Track Python Programmer Track SQL fundamentals Track SQL Server Fundamantal Track Data Engineering Track  Radacad  Power BI From Rookie to Rockstar (in progress)  Futurelearn  Python in High Performance Computing (in progress) Object-oriented Programming in Python: Create Your Own Adventure Game  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning materials</title>
      <link>/learning-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 15:52:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learning-resources/</guid>
      <description>Here is some learning sources for Python, R, Power BI, etc.
Learning sites:
 DataCamp EdX Coursera Linuxacedemy Community edition Hackerrank Hackerearth KataCoda CS50 series from Harvard Kaggle  Tutorials, blogs and other sites
 Python Master Guide Slither in to Python Real Python Data36 Python Data Science Handbook Trey Hunner Matt Layman Freecodecamp news Radacad for Power BI  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My DataCamp Projects</title>
      <link>/project/datacamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 10:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/datacamp/</guid>
      <description>My solved DataCamp projects My Jupyter Notebooks can be found here and here.
Python &amp;ndash; DATA MANIPULATION   Predicting Credit Card Approvals: Build a machine learning model to predict if a credit card application will get approved.
  A Visual History of Nobel Prize Winners: Explore a dataset from Kaggle containing a century&amp;rsquo;s worth of Nobel Laureates. Who won? Who got snubbed?
  The GitHub History of the Scala Language: Find the true Scala experts by exploring its development history in Git and GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My mini rpg project</title>
      <link>/project/mini_rpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 10:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/mini_rpg/</guid>
      <description>My mini rpg project This is a fun project to practice OOP in Python. The main idea is from FutureLearn.
Aim of this game to get 3 friends, most of the time you have to fight with them to become friendly. Possible commands to move the player from room to room are north, south, west, east. Other commands talk, fight, check, backpack.
Commands (after &amp;gt; sign):
 north, south, west, east talk fight check backback  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geolocate IP addresses and visualize using folium</title>
      <link>/ip-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 15:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ip-post/</guid>
      <description>This blog post was originally published in https://adventuresindatachaosblog.wordpress.com/2018/12/22/geolocate-ip-addresses-and-visualize-using-folium/ 22/12/2018.
How you can find location data based on IP addresses Geographical mapping of an IP address can provide location information (country, city, longitude, latitude, etc.) for you. A large number of geolocation providers could be found on the Internet. Some of them are free (in many cases the provided information is limited), and some of them let you automate your requests. I have chosen the IP Geolocation API (ip-api.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 14:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>About me Since 2015 I have learnt a lot about Data Science, Programming, Data Engineering in my free time. Now I try to collect my knowledge as posts, as reminders for myself. I know some R, Python, SQL. I use Fedora everyday for several years. With my friends - Google, Stackoverflow - I can troubleshoot a lot of things. I am an Environmental Engineer and have PhD in Chemistry.
During my learning journey I attended several courses and used a lot of platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact You can connect me via LinkedIn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My short projects</title>
      <link>/project/myprojects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/myprojects/</guid>
      <description>About project My short python scripts can be found here</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>